Whoever told you that you can start
trading Forex with zero dollars is plain
[__] lying to you. It's like trying
to get abs without going to the gym.
It's like trying to get girls without
looking good. It is not happening. It is
a lie. It is not real. So, the real
truth is that you need at least a bare
minimum of $100. This is the lowest
amount of the entry barrier that should
be even legal to enter trading into the
markets. Anything below, it's not
realistic because you need money to make
money. And to even prove that concept, I
personally about a year ago, I turned a
$100 into a million all documented live.
So I am a living proof that the bare
minimum you need to start trading is a
$100. So let me actually explain to you
how trading the markets work because a
lot of people are confused and they
don't have a clear understanding of what
it is. Trading the markets is very
simple. Markets are either going to go
up or they're going to go down. And us
as traders, we're simply going to bet
that it's going to continue to go up or
bet that it's going to continue to go
down. At no given point are you actually
buying currencies and exchanging them
for other that doesn't exist. That is
not how trading forex or trading the
foreign exchange market works. You put
money into an account and then you bet
if a market goes up and then you bet if
a market goes down. If you win, you win
off of somebody else's losses somewhere
in the $6.3 trillion foreign exchange
market. And if you lose, well, you
participate that loss to somebody else
on the other side that is winning.
Because if you're betting that
something's going to go up, somebody
somewhere in the side of the world is
betting that it's going to go down. So
now that you understand basic foundation
how the markets work and you understand
that you need a bare minimum of $100 to
start. There's actually two ways on
where you can take these $100 because
you need money to make money. The first
way you can implement these $100 is by
simply putting them into a broker
account. You get your leverage up to 1
to500 1 to 1,000 which basically
essentially gives you more leverage on
that $100 which gives you buying power
of 10 $1,000 and even more. And then
there you can just trade your personal
$1,000 or you can take those $100 and go
to whatever prop firm in the industry
that best suits your liking and you can
buy a challenge. You can buy a challenge
for a $5,000 challenge or a $10,000
challenge. Depends on what prop firm
compan is out there. And with those same
$100, you have equivalent to a $5,000
account that you have to pass an
evaluation process in order for you to
get access to that account. If you fail
their valuation process, you will then
in turn lose your $100 initial
investment. Or you can go to your
personal account, which you can just
deposit into an account, and you have
immediate access to your $100 with
buying power of up to $1,000, even
$10,000. Meaning, you can bet with these
$100 as if they were to be a,000 or as
if they were to be $10,000. That is if
you were to up your leverage, which
obviously there is a double-edged sword
on that. that means your $100 is more
exposed and you're more prone to losing
it a lot quicker. But if you're on the
right side of the market, then you'll be
able to reap the rewards of that risk
where in turn, if you were to take those
$100 into a proper account, you don't
get immediate access into those $5,000
that you're buying of the challenge. You
have to pass the evaluation process. You
have to follow the strict rules and then
you get access to $5,000, but then you
receive a profit split on both. I have
tried it myself personally. The prop
firm route made me understand how to
properly follow my risk management
rules, properly follow daily and total
loss limit rules and they made me
appreciate how to have large amounts of
money. But where I actually became a
very successful trader and I actually
grew my net worth. I made a lot of money
in trading is on my own personal account
simply because I have access to it right
away and I'm able to make more money off
of my money and I kind of make my own
rules since it's my money. I'm not using
other people's money. So, now that
you've taken your $100 either to your
broker or you've taken it to your prop
firm of your choice, the next step is
you need to know the platforms to use
inside of these markets for you to
actually determine if you want to enter
a trade or not. And for me personally,
I've educated on many different
industries and niches. And trading
specifically is one of those industries
that has an excess amount of tools,
excess amount of platforms that do not
help you when it comes to making a
decision. if this trade is going to go
up or down. There's endless websites on
indicators, endless websites on AI, on
recording, on journaling. There's just
so many different platforms that are not
necessary and will not help your trading
at all. And a lot of traders that are
new into the journey get confused and
think that the more subscriptions they
pay and the more websites and the more
platforms and the more tools they use,
the more profit they're going to be. And
that's not the case. It's actually very
simple the platforms that you need. All
you have to do is just focus on these
and focus on your strategy, which is
key, but later on that into the video.
So, the tools and platforms that you're
going to need, the first one is broker
profit of choice. That's where you're
going to be depositing and withdrawing
your profits. The second one is going to
be trading, a platform where you can see
every single market globally. You can
literally see from stocks, cryptos,
currencies, indices. You can see every
single market in a detailed candlestick
way, in a line pattern way. And
basically any format that you would want
to see the market, Trading View is going
to display that. And this is where
you're going to spend 99% of your time
on this platform reading the markets
determining if you want to enter a trade
or not. Train View is the number one
platform recognized globally. The third
platform that is needed but not really
as you continue to go on through your
journey that is going to be
Forexfactory.com.
Forex Factory has a calendar which lets
you know what lowrisk and high impact
fundamentals are going to be coming
right ahead. This is so you can have an
idea if you should be interested in
entering a trade, if you should be
interested in exiting a trade early, or
if you should just simply sit on your
hands and wait to see what's going to
happen. Forex Factory lets you know the
difference between a high news event and
a low news event. So you don't have to
go out there online and waste time
reading these articles just for you to
get the same information that this
website does. And this is not an ad for
any of these platforms. They're just the
ones that I personally have been using
for the last 7 years of my journey and
have worked phenomenally. And I
understand you need 100 bucks. You need
the platforms. Now all you need is to be
profitable. and to be profitable. This
is what 99% of traders are simply not
prepared for the journey ahead of them
because they don't understand what you
need to do in order for you to become
profitable. And for you to become
profitable, you have to do many things.
But these are the basis of becoming a
profitable trader for you to actually
make money with those 100 bucks. And in
order for you to be profitable, you need
a trading strategy. It is as simple as
it is. trading strategy, a trading plan,
a list of confluences, whatever you want
to call it. You need to understand what
you're looking at when the market comes.
You cannot just go to the gym and by
looking at the weights expect to get
fit. It's not going to happen. You need
to have a workout plan. You need to have
a diet plan. You have to count your
macros. You need to make sure that
you're actually doing something that
works well. for you to be profitable and
for you to actually make money, there's
three key foundations in order for you
to know that you're having a profitable
strategy. And without these three key
things, your strategy, your trading
plan, your confluences are literally
pointless. The first one is going to be
patterns. Your strategy needs to consist
of some type of patterns. Now, I'm not
talking about all of these crazy
harmonic ABCD patterns, all of these
crazy different tweezer patterns, hedge
patterns. No, I'm talking about
something that has happened in the
market structure in the past that has
shown this same exact thing over and
over again where we can anticipate it
for the future. A pattern is something
that is tending to repeat itself. If
your strategy constantly is repeating
itself, you're good. You have an edge.
it should continue to happen again in
the future. The second thing that you're
going to need, and it is extremely
crucial, is going to be risk management.
If you do not have a profitable
riskmanagement strategy, you can have
the best strategy in the world with the
most amount of patterns that repeat
themselves. But if your risk management
is not on point, those times that you
lose because you will lose in the
markets. It is inevitable. We are in a
business. In order for you to get
something in return, you have to put
risk up. And it's never going to be
guaranteed. And the risk management will
define how good your strategy actually
is. Because you can have a 50/50
strategy and your risk management will
make you profitable. And these two tied
together leads me to the third one which
is even more important. That is going to
be the mind, your psychology. You can
have the best strategy in the world. You
can have the best risk management
strategy in the world. But if your
mindset is not in a profitable trader
mindset, you will never make money in
the markets because some traders just
cannot accept losing. Some traders
cannot accept not doing anything. You
need to understand that the markets
aren't tradable when you want. The
markets are tradable when they give you
an opportunity. And some traders just
cannot fathom to get their hands and for
them to sit on their hands. They
constantly want to be clicking buttons.
They want to feel like they're involved
into the markets. That is one of the
biggest issues across the board from
beginner, intermediate, and even
experienced traders. Just don't
constantly want to be involved. So, you
need to have the right mindset for you
to be able to control this strategy
correctly. You have the best strategy in
the world, but if you don't have the
mind to execute it, you have nothing.
And this takes me to step four, which is
even more important and is where I would
say arguably I got a little bit of luck.
And that is going to be time. You need
to have time for this to play out. You
need time in order for you to learn
this. You need to have time in order for
you to practice it. And you need to give
time its time and damn thing. Because if
you do not learn it, practice it, and
then execute it over the course of 3,
four, five, 6 months, then you're simply
never going to give it enough time for
it to work. Time is going to be your
best friend, but it's also going to be
your worst enemy. Your worst enemy
because you're not going to want to
learn this in the next 2 3 months. It's
going to be your best friend when you
already understand it and you can see
these opportunities come to you and then
when the trades start going into your
profit. It's not going to be your best
friend when you're 2 3 days without
taking a trade and you feel like you've
just been wasting time. Time is going to
be crucial across your whole entire
journey. And when it comes to execute
these trades, time is in your favor and
it's also against you. But the basis of
time is going to be you need to give it
time to learn. Depending on how
available you are, we need to dedicate
at least 1 to two hours every single day
to it. When it comes to practicing it,
you need to dedicate at least one to two
hours every single day to practice it in
the effective times. Because if you're
trading out of the session, you're
simply not doing anything. The best
example that I want to give you is like,
oh, I'm only available to go work out at
the gym at 8:00 from 8 to 9. And you go
to the gym and the gym is closed. You're
not doing anything. You are making the
time at the wrong time. So you need to
practice and execute this at the right
time. And this is very crucial to your
journey because if you're not executing
at the right time, you're not practicing
it how it should be. And that is all
very important but not as important as
the time of you letting time do its
thing for you to go through the journey
of a profitable trader. Journey of a
profitable trader is not like this. It
is a journey. Journeys have ups and
downs and you're going to see the beauty
of that journey. You're going to look
back at the mistakes you've done. You're
going to then look forward to the ups of
the future. But all of this by simply
giving everything time. Everybody's
timeline is different. For me, it took
me 2 years to be profitable. I have
students that it takes them 2 months.
Just depends on your availability and
how much you actually understand this.
Everybody's time is different based off
of your availability. It's really all it
is. And last and definitely not least,
one of the most key principles that you
need in order for you to make it in
trading, especially with just a hundred
bucks, is going to be you need a pair of
[__] balls. Without balls, you will
not succeed in this industry. You need
balls to put some money up at risk. You
need some balls to handle some losses.
You need some balls to hold some
profits. You need balls from this point
until the end of your life. If you have
a pair of [__] balls, you will
succeed in trading because a lot of risk
is associated with this. A lot of
sleepless nights, a lot of rewards are
reaped with it. And if you properly
don't have your pair of balls placed,
you're either going to continue to lose
and quit or when you win, you're going
to get too excited and then you're going
to lose the focus that you have in your
journey. You do not have to be books
smart. You do not have to have a degree.
You do not have to have a friend with
you. You don't have to have a book that
you read. Maybe a little bit of this,
but that's later into your journey. You
don't need anything other than your
willingness of you showing up every
single day, even when things get tough.
You don't need anything else other than
just you in front of your computer every
single day until you put the time into
understanding this journey. Now, I'm not
here to tell you that this is easy. It's
not. It's going to be really hard, but
everything that goes through a hard
journey ends up having an amazing reward
towards the end. All it takes is for you
to have some courage, for you to have a
pair of balls and some time. So, if
you're ready to take that chance, you
want to make sure that you can do it
properly. You don't want to waste time
on learning strategies that don't work,
on being part of communities that aren't
motivated and aren't effective. That's
why my success rate is through the roof
with my students where they're
constantly making anywhere from $1,000
to $1,500 a week using this set and
forget strategy where I hop on calls
with them every single Sunday. I share
with them my trade ideas where I'm
constantly inside of the community
answering questions or sharing new trade
updates on personal trades that I'm
taking or at least into having results
very similar to mines because we're
going to be trading the exact same
markets. So, if you want to be part of a
community that shares this exact
strategy to the tea, so you can have
results just like them, just watch the
link in the video below. It is literally
a free video. You're going to understand
exactly what we are about and what this
set and forget strategy is. With that
being said, thank you very much for
being part of this video. Make sure to
hit that like and subscribe button. I'll
see you guys on the next